（郷田武蔵(ごうだ　むさし)）
肉改～！
Body improvement!
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on! Fight!
（部員たち）
ファイオ～ ファイオ～
ファイオ～ ファイ…
Psychic powers don't make a man appealing.
（モブ）
男の魅力は超能力にあらず
And so, in order to change myself,
僕は自分を変えるために
肉体改造部へ入部しました
I joined the Body Improvement Club.
Body improvement!
（郷田）
肉改～！
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on!
（部員たち）
ファイオ～！ ファイオ～！
（モブ）
ハア… ハア…
（郷田）
肉改～！
Body improvement!
Fight... on... Fight... on...
（モブ）
ファイ オ～ ファイ オ～…
（郷田）
ん？ これは いかん
This isn't good.
He must be anemic.
貧血だな
Sh-Showwy......
あっ すいません
ああっ…
Mob's Stamina: 0%
～
Mob Psycho
There's definitely something wrong with him.
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
やっぱり変よ 彼
（暗田）
普通 あの場で肉体改造部を選ぶ？
Who would choose the
Body Improvement Club in that situation?
Come train!
The Body Improvement Club wants you!
（犬川(いぬかわ)）
う～ん まあ この前のことは
もう いいじゃないですか
Well, let's not dwell on the past.
Come on. It's your turn, President Kurata.
（犬川）
ほら 暗田部長の番ですよ
お～っす
Hey.
Body Improvement!! Lower Body Strengthening Month!!
Ah, Musashi-san!
（一同）
わあっ 武蔵さん
Thank you so much for
letting us use this room!
部屋を使わせていただき
誠にありがとうございます！
You don't have to grovel...
（郷田）
別に 土下座せんでも
うちは筋トレ器具の置き場に
使えれば それでいいんだ
All we want the room for
is to store our equipment.
（暗田）
あっ それは…
What's with him?
Oh, Kageyama passed out.
（郷田）
ああ 影山(かげやま)が倒れた
Sorry, but could you watch over him?
すまないが
見ててやってくれるか？
ハア… ハア…
Seriously, dude.
（暗田）
ていうか あんた
Why did you join the Body Improvement Club?
なんで 肉改部に入ったのよ？
僕 昔から運動音痴で
走るのとか遅いんです
I've never been the most athletic guy.
And I'm a really slow runner.
It's because I've relied on
my psychic powers for everything.
今まで 超能力に頼ってきたから…
Huh? What kind of excuse is that?
はあ？
何よ その言い訳
If you actually have psychic powers,
I'd love to see them, jeez.
（暗田）
本当に超能力があるなら
見せてほしいわよ まったく！
（モブ）
ああ…
（雉子林(きじばやし)）うっ…
（暗田）ひゃあ
（猿田(さるた)）うっ！
（犬川）えっ？
Is that enough for you to believe me?
こんなのでも
信じてもらえますか？
This is heavy!
これ 重っ！
Seriously? He could only bend spoons before!
（犬川）
マジかよ
スプーン 曲げる程度だったのに！
（暗田）
アウ！
Please! Help me make my dream come true!
お… お願い
私の夢に協力してちょうだい
えっ？
Believe it or not...
何を隠そう
My dream is to contact and interact with
extraterrestrial lifeforms!
この暗田トメの夢は
宇宙のどこかにいる地球外生命と
交信 接触すること
Telepathy
At first, I followed a guidebook
and tried it out, but it didn't work.
最初は本を読んで
実践を試みていたけど
何の成果も得られず
And before I knew it,
I was just lazing around...
いつしか
ダラダラ過ごすようになっていた
But now,
しかし 今
ここに突破口が見えたわ！
I've got my big break!
Mob-kun, let's research telepathy together,
モブ君 私たちと共に
テレパシーを研究し
seek new life, and boldly go
where no man has gone before!
無限の宇宙との邂逅(かいこう)を果たすのよ！
Actually, I've got weight lifting to do.
いや 僕 筋トレあるんで
Wait, why?
おい なんでだよ
I'm burning with passion here.
Why are you so ice-cold?
私の情熱に対して冷めすぎだろ
I've finally found something
that I want to do.
（モブ）
僕は やっと やりたいことを
見つけたんです
それが筋肉 付けることだって
言うの？
What, putting on muscle?
超能力があるのに？
But you have psychic powers...
Actually, maybe I should say I want to
become more appealing as a man.
男の魅力を身に付けたくて
…とでも 言えばいいんですかね？
モブ君 モテたいの？
You want to be popular, Mob-kun?
えっ！
いや… 別に…
No, not really...
Well, you won't be.
（暗田）モテねえよ
（モブ）え…
Even if you gain muscle,
you won't become popular.
（暗田）
筋肉を付けても あんたはモテない
Not a chance!
絶対にだ
Th-Then what should I do?
じゃあ… じゃあ どうすれば？
Read girls' minds using telepathy.
（暗田）
テレパシーで女の心を読むの！
Then you'll be super popular.
そうすりゃ モテモテよ！
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
What? Telepathy?
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
なに？ テレパシー？
（霊幻）
俺は ちょっと できないな～
Yeah, I can't really do that.
I can hear the voices of spirits, though...
霊の声は聞くことは できるんだが
What brought this on?
（霊幻）
でも なんで急に？
何となくですよ
I was just wondering...
心をのぞきたい相手が いるのか？
Is there someone whose mind you want to read?
えっ？
女か？
A girl, huh?
My, my, Mob-kun...
おやおや モブ君
分かりやすいねえ
You're so easy to read.
Well, every middle school boy
wants to be popular,
まあ モテたいのは
全男子中学生の共通観念だから
so there's no need to be embarrassed.
恥じることはないぞ
Even I want to be popular.
かく言う俺も
モテたくて しょうがないしな
It's not like I want to be popular.
（モブ）
別に モテなくたっていいんだ
I just want to get close to Tsubomi-chan.
ツボミちゃんと仲良くなれれば…
Pardon me, young man.
（仮面女）
もし？ ちょっと そこの少年
Something must be troubling you.
（仮面女）
悩んでますねえ
だって 笑顔がないもの
You aren't laughing or smiling.
いや…
No...
I can tell.
（仮面女）
分かります
勉強のことで悩んでるんでしょ？
You're worried about your studies, right?
I'm not.
悩んでないです
Of course not. It's not your studies...
（仮面女）
そうなのよ！ 勉強じゃないのよ
う～ん…
Yes, it must be hard
dealing with family issues.
家庭のことで悩むのは
つらいでしょうねえ
Actually, I don't have any.
（モブ）
別に大丈夫です
Of course you don't.
It must be your health... No...
（仮面女）
そうなのよね
やっぱり健康… じゃなくて…
It's about love.
恋の悩み？
How did you know?!
なんで 分かったんですか？
If you want to resolve your troubles,
come with me.
（仮面女）
悩みを解決したいなら
私についてきなさい
Actually, I have to head home.
（モブ）
いや もう帰ろうかと…
You'll be popular.
（仮面女）
モテますよ
I'll go!
行きます
An Invite to a Meeting
~Simply Put, I Just Want to Be Popular~
I belong to a brand-new religious order
that came into existence last month.
（仮面女）
うちはね つい先月に作られた
全く新しい宗教なんですよ
Religious order?
（モブ）
宗教？
It's called (LOL).
（仮面女）
教団名は （笑）(カッコワライ)
Founded by our leader, Dimple-sama,
教祖 エクボ様が設立した—
it's the happiest and trendiest
gathering of the century!
今世紀 最もハッピーで
トレンディーな集いなんです
Dimple-sama has the mysterious power
to make anyone laugh immediately.
エクボ様は不思議な“力”で
どんな者も
たちまち笑顔にしてしまうのです！
それで どうやったら
モテるんですか？
So, how do I become popular?
（仮面女）
フッフフフ
Now, now, don't be so hasty.
まあ そう 気構えずに
(LOL) is in no way a suspicious group.
（笑）は 決して怪しい団体では
ありませんから！
(LOL)
Wow, there are a lot of people.
（モブ）
おお～ たくさん集まってる
I wonder if they all want to be popular, too.
みんな モテたい 一心なのかな？
Oh, are you new, too?
（男性信者）おや 君も新参かい？
（モブ）え？
Huh?
（女性信者）
だったら ステージに上がって！
Then get on stage.
なんでですか？
Why?
Come on, now.
（信者たち）
ほらほら！
早く！
Hurry.
Heave ho, heave ho!
ワッショイ ワッショイ！
I have no idea what's going on anymore.
（モブ）
何だろう？ この状況
Huh? Mob-kun?
（米里(めざと)イチ）あれ？ モブ君？
（モブ）あ…
Do you recognize me?
I'm Mezato from your class.
私 分かる？
同じクラスの米里よ
Mezato
Ichi
Ah, I've never talked to her before.
（モブ）
あ… この人 初会話だ
Did they lure you in?
（米里）勧誘されたの？
（モブ）えっと 僕は…
Um, I...
He's here!
（男性信者）
来たぞ！ エクボ様だ！
It's Dimple-sama!
（男性信者）
エクボ様！
（信者たち）
ああ～！
Everyone...
（エクボ）
皆さん…
Are you laughing?
笑ってますか～？
Are you sufficiently warmed up now?
（エクボ）
温まってきたかな？
Why don't we take off those masks, then?
じゃあ そろそろ外しちゃおうか？
（エクボ）
ピカ～ン！
Sparkle!
You're all smiling so brightly.
（エクボ）
みんな いい笑顔だ
（中年男）
不気味な連中だな
What a creepy bunch...
スト～ップ！
Stop!
Today, we have three new
smilemates joining us.
（エクボ）
今日 ここに
３人のスマイルメイトが
加わることになりました
Give them a big hand!
拍手！
（拍手）
はあ？ 何だ？
Huh? What?
Hey, don't...
ちょっと勝手に…
In order to accept happiness,
you must set your hearts free.
幸せを受け入れるためには
心を解放しなければなりません
But your hearts are locked up.
（エクボ）
しかし あなたたちの心には
鍵が かかっている
See? It's completely obvious
why you're unhappy.
ほら！ 不幸の原因は 一目瞭然
You aren't laughing.
笑顔がない
（信者たち）
おお～
（エクボ）
笑いなさい
Laugh. If you laugh even in pain,
苦しくても 笑っていれば
鍵は外れるのです
your hearts will be unlocked!
And once they have been set free,
解放された心には余裕が生まれ
your hearts will have the ability to
accept happiness as it comes.
素直に幸せを
受け入れるようになるのです
In order to have a happy life,
you must have a hearty laugh!
笑顔を維持することが
幸せを維持する条件なのです
That is the teaching of (LOL).
それらが 我ら（笑）の教え
ケッ 笑って幸せになれるなら
楽なもんだぜ
Hah. How I wish people could
be happy just by laughing.
Who might this be?
（エクボ）
この方は？
We found him on a park bench.
（女性信者）
公園のベンチで
座りほうけていました
How sad. A victim of the recession!
（エクボ）
何と不幸な不景気の犠牲者！
It's no wonder you've lost your smile.
笑えなくなるのも
無理はないでしょう
But worry not!
でも 大丈夫！
Let's put on this smile mask and fix that.
スマイルマスクを かぶって
矯正しましょう
Hey, what are you...
（中年男）
おい 何を…
Hey...
（米里）
ちょっと！
This is our way of saving you.
これは救済措置なのです
ただ あなたに
笑顔になってほしいのです
We just want you to smile.
（中年男）
うおっ
（モブ）
うん？
No resistance.
（エクボ）
無抵抗
Lastly, the girl.
最後に女の子
さっきから 何か言いたそうな顔だ
It appears that you have something to say.
宗教団体（笑） 先月に設立？
Religious order (LOL), established last month?
You managed to attract this many
followers in just one month?
（米里）
たった１か月で
こんな人数の盲信者を
囲ったっていうの？
I don't believe that!
怪しいわ！
Oh? And you are...?
（エクボ）
ほ～う 君は？
I work for Salt Middle School's newspaper!
塩(しお)中学校 新聞部
２年１組 米里です！
I'm Mezato from Class 2-1!
I'm reporting on the bad rumor
concerning you guys.
あなたたちの悪いウワサを
取材させてもらいます！
悪いウワサ？
Bad rumor?
That you're using group hypnosis to
brainwash and force people into joining.
集団催眠による洗脳や
強迫観念の植え付けよ
She has the nerve to say that
after sneaking in by herself.
（エクボ）
単身で乗り込み しゃべる度胸
すばらしい
Splendid.
Let me provide you with proof, then.
（エクボ）
では １つ証明しよう
Please take a look at
the gentleman from earlier.
先ほどの男性を見てください
A few minutes ago, he was a very sad man.
数分前は不幸な人間でしたが…
Sparkle!
ピカ～ン！
What a wonderful smile!
いいスマイルです！
How funny...
He's laughing? Why?
（米里）
笑いだした　どうして？
（エクボ）
彼は 今まさに 幸せをつかみました
He has now truly grasped happiness.
どうですか？ お嬢さん
What do you think, young lady?
True, they didn't do anything bad...
（米里）
確かに 何も悪いことはしてないわ
I'm sure you'll find a job.
（男性信者）
きっと仕事も見つかりますよ
But something's still off.
（米里）
…にしても やっぱり変よ
There's something strange in the air here...
この空間には何かある
This story is a bit too much
for me to handle,
（米里）
この取材 私の手に余ると
判断したので
so if you'll excuse me...
ここで 一度 失礼します
That won't do.
ダメです
You infiltrated (LOL) and
doubted our smiles for no reason.
あなたは
いたずらに（笑）に踏み込み
我々のスマイルに疑問を呈した
I'm terribly sorry.
全面的に謝ります
I won't write about you in the school paper.
学校新聞の記事にはしません
That is not enough!
It won't ease our hard feelings!
（エクボ）
不十分です
このままでは 後腐れが出来ます
We won't let you leave until you laugh.
（エクボ）
帰しませんよ 笑うまで
I-I don't really feel
like laughing right now.
う… 笑う気分じゃありません
それに 今 私が笑ったところで
ただの愛想笑いだわ
And if I forced myself to right now,
it wouldn't be sincere.
Start with a smile.
まずは形からです
嫌です！
No! I don't want to lie to myself.
自分にウソは つきたくないもの！
Hey!
（米里）
ちょっと！
あ… あっ あっ
What is this?!
何 これ？
H-Huh? I'm...
（米里）
あっ あれ？ 勝手に…
No! Don't!
いや！ ダメ！
いや～！
No!
Sparkle!
ピカ～ン！
最高のスマイルではありませんか！
Look at that magnificent smile!
Congratulations!
You seem completely different now.
No, I...
（米里）
いや 私… そんな…
What a gleaming smile.
No...
（米里）
何？ この感覚
What is this feeling?
We're all smiling,
and it feels really nice...
みんなも私も笑ってて
何だか心地いい～！
But no! I don't really want to smile!
でも 違う！
ホントは笑いたくないのに！
Someone save me!
助けて！ 誰か！
Um, excuse me.
（モブ）
あの… すみません
Mob-kun!
（米里）
モブ君！
So the theme here is smiling and happiness?
（モブ）
これって 笑顔とか幸せがテーマで
It doesn't have anything to do
with being popular?
モテるかどうかは別の話ですよね？
May I leave now, then?
帰っていいですか？
Who's that?
彼は？
He looked troubled on his way home
from school, so I brought him here.
（仮面女）
下校中 悩んだ顔をしていたので
連れてきました
It seems he's having trouble with love.
恋の悩みがあるようです
I'm not really troubled, though.
（モブ）
別に 悩んでないです
He's not smiling!
（エクボ）
笑っていない！
Are you telling me that
the smile mask didn't work?
スマイルマスクが
効いていないというのか？
Huh? He's not smiling?
（どよめき）
Bye.
（モブ）
じゃあ
W-Wait!
ま… 待ちなさい！
Do you plan to live the rest
of your life with that face?
（エクボ）
一生 そんな顔で
生きるつもりですか？
君は人生を損している！
You are missing out on life!
（モブ）
う～ん
My dad said that
"people who've never smoked before
僕の父は
“たばこを知らないヤツは
人生の半分 損してる”って
are missing out on half of their lives."
言ってました
It made me realize that everyone has
a different idea of "missing out."
損って感覚も
人によるんだなって思いました
（エクボ）
くっ… そういう話じゃないのに！
That's not what I'm talking about.
(LOL) is the start line for me to become
a religious figure for all of humanity!
（笑）は 私が全人類の
信仰対象となるための出発点なのだ
I can't let this trip me up!
つまずいている場合じゃない！
I just want you to know
how wonderful it is to smile.
私はただ 笑うことのすばらしさを
知ってもらいたくてね
別に大丈夫です
That's okay.
Th-Then would you like to
play a game before you leave?
（エクボ）
じゃ… じゃあ
ゲームでも していかないかい？
A staring contest. You'll have a staring
contest with three of my smile leaders.
（エクボ）
にらめっこだ
うちのスマイルリーダー３人と
にらめっこ
Smile Leaders
You'll all drink milk,
and the first to laugh loses.
牛乳を口に含んで
先に笑ったほうが負け
What do you think?
どうだい？
Mob-kun, this is a trap!
（米里）
モブ君 これはワナよ！
Progress Toward
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 58%
（モブ）
ああ…
Mob Psycho 100
Are you ready? If you laugh, you lose.
（審判）
準備はいい？ 笑ったら負けだよ
Why did you accept the challenge?!
（米里）
なんで 受けて立つのよ！
Mob loves milk.
（ナレーション）
モブは牛乳が好きだった
（審判）
レディ…
Ready, go!
ゴー！
（エクボ）
なんでだよ！
Why?!
Go!
（審判）
ゴー！
（エクボ）
バカな！
Impossible...
Those two are pathetic.
（スマイルリーダー）
２人とも 情けないなあ
With my smiling powers, I'll throw
that boy into a smiley maelstrom...
私の笑顔力で少年を
ビッグスマイルの渦に陥れて…
Smile Leader No. 3
ぶほっ！
O-Oh, I see!
（エクボ）
そうか！
Forcing them to laugh all the time backfired!
ふだんから笑顔を矯正していたのが
裏目に…
（モブ）
んん… 勝ったので帰ります
I won, so I'm going home now.
Wait!
（エクボ）待て
（モブ）あ？
You'll have to face me now!
私が相手だ
（信者たち）
おお！ 何と！
エクボ様 じきじきに？
What?
Dimple-sama is going to face him himself?
I will not let you win.
（エクボ）
勝ちは絶対に譲らない
I will make you spit out that milk!
必ず牛乳を吹いてもらうよ
Ready, go!
レディ ゴー！
うううっ！
That milk...
（ナレーション）
その牛乳…
clearly had something mixed in.
明らかに 何かが混じっていた
He laughed!
笑った～！
（信者たち）
笑った！
吹いた！
He spit it out!
Nothing less from our Dimple-sama!
（信者たち）
さすがエクボ様だ！
また１人 救った！
He saved another!
Even I'm starting to have fun now...
（米里）
私も楽しくなってきちゃった
（モブ）
ハア ハア ハア…
僕は… 笑ってない
I... didn't laugh.
Huh? My smile...
あっ あれ？ 笑顔が…
Wait, why am I here again?
（男性信者）
つうか なんで
ここにいるんだっけ？
（エクボ）
ふん！
Because it's so much fun!
（男性信者）
楽しいから いるんじゃないか！
You just...
君 今…
No, he couldn't possibly have
undone my hypnosis.
（エクボ）
いや 私の催眠波を かき消すなど
ありえん！
But why can't I make him laugh?
だが なぜ
笑わせることが できない？
I have no choice. I'll have to go all out.
しかたない　ここは力業だ
皆さん 閉じ込められた彼の笑顔を
救い出してあげましょう
Everyone! Let us save
the laughter trapped within him!
If he stayed this way,
I'd feel too sorry for him!
このままでは不幸すぎる
（信者たち）
うわ～！
すばらしい！
How wonderful!
Dimple-sama!
Let us laugh!
（女性信者）
笑いましょうよ
Hey, wait. I...
（モブ）
ちょっと 待ってよ！ 僕は…
Smile and live a good life!
See? You don't have a single enemy here,
（エクボ）
ほ～ら 君の敵は
誰１人として いないのに
so what exactly are you fighting?
一体 何と戦っているんだ？
（モブ）
うう…
空気を読みなさい
Get a clue.
（モブ）
あっ
Hey, Mob.
（少年１）
おい モブ
Why do you always look so bored?
なんで つまんなそうにしてんだよ
Huh?
（モブ）
え？
If you're bored, go home.
（少年１）
退屈なら帰れよ
But I'm not.
そんなこと ないけど？
（少年２）
ブリ～ン
You're the only one who's not laughing.
（少年３）
１人 笑ってないんですけど？
Mob-kun.
（ツボミ）
モブ君
（モブ）
あ… ツボミちゃん
Tsubomi-chan.
（ツボミ）
空気 読もうよ
Get a clue.
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 74%
私の真の“力”を お見せしますよ
I will show you my true power.
Now, laugh!
さあ 笑え～！
There it is!
（男性信者）
出た！
It's Dimple-sama's divine power!
（男性信者）
エクボ様の神通力だ！
What?!
（エクボ）
なに？
ふん！
なぜだ？
Why?!
Why aren't you laughing?!
なぜ 笑わない？
私の“力”が効かないというのか？
Are you saying my powers don't work on you?
笑えよ 笑えよ！ 小僧 笑え～！
Laugh! Come on, laugh, you brat! Laugh!
I see. He has psychic powers, too.
（モブ）
そうか この人も超能力を…
Are you a corpse?!
死体か？ てめえは！
Your powers can't make me laugh.
教祖さんの“力”では
笑うことができない
I don't hate it.
I just couldn't, even if I wanted to.
嫌いじゃない
できないんだ… したくても
I don't mean anything bad by it, though.
でも これは
悪気が あるわけじゃないんです
I see... He...
（エクボ）
そうか こいつ…
ヘッ 感情がないのか？ 小僧
You must not have emotions, brat.
恋の悩みだとか言ってたな
They mentioned that you were
having troubles with love.
そんな性質(たち)じゃ 好きな女と
一緒に笑えないだろう？
With a personality like that, you won't
be able to laugh with the girl you like.
The feelings of people resonate
with one another, you know.
人の感情は
他者に呼応する仕組みだからな
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 88%
But you're unable to do that.
（エクボ）
だが お前は
それが できない
You can't cry together, or even be moved.
（エクボ）
一緒に泣けない　感動もできない
You'll be forever alone.
お前は永久に孤独だ
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 92%
I'll give you one last chance...
特別に 最後のチャンスをやる
Laugh!
笑え
アハ～！
Make me laugh with your psychic powers.
（モブ）
その超能力で笑わせてくれよ
（エクボ）
うっ！
お前… そうか！
You... I see.
So you have similar powers...
俺と似た“力”を…
最も平和で血の流れない宗教形態を
選んだつもりだが
I thought I picked a peaceful religious order
that'd cause the least bloodshed,
but you're in my way, brat.
邪魔だ 小僧
I'll have to get rid of the outsider
that brings chaos to this environment.
輪を乱す異分子は
排除せねばならない！
Thank goodness. You're not a person.
よかった　人じゃないんだね
僕に“空気を読め”なんて
恐ろしいことを言ったのが
Thank goodness the one who said
something as horrible as "get a clue"
was an evil spirit.
悪霊でよかった
My followers!
（エクボ）
信者たちよ
そいつを生かして帰すな！
Do not let him leave alive!
A strong commanding signal...
（モブ）
強い命令信号
うっ うう…
（ツボミ）
モブ君
Mob-kun.
Get a clue.
空気 読もうよ
There is an esper present here.
（ナレーション）
ここに１人の超能力者がいる
A grade schooler called
"Mob" by those around him.
周囲から“モブ”と呼ばれる小学生
Even though he's blessed with
tremendous powers,
彼は 強力な“力”を
持っていながらも
he's subconsciously always avoided
trying to display those powers.
自ら それを披露することを
無意識に避けるようになっていた
As he grew,
成長を重ねるごとに
he gradually realized
how dangerous his powers were.
自分の“力”が危険であることに
徐々に気付いていったのだ
When people are unable to act
or do as they please,
好きなように
思うがまま動けないとなると
their emotions come to a halt.
常に感情に
ブレーキを かけた状態になる
Mob hasn't realized that his aversion to
using his powers has become a complex.
“力”の使用を避ける生活が
コンプレックスになっていることに
モブ本人は気付いていない
Calm
Satisfaction
Admiration
Affinity
Curiosity
Hate
Relief
The emotions that are locked away
deep inside Mob's heart
抑圧された感情は
モブの心の奥深くで
expand little by little.
少～しずつ 膨らんでいく
However, there is a limit to
how much his emotions can take
内であふれ出し
暴れる感情のセーブにも
before leaking out and going wild.
限界許容量がある
And now, an emotion was swirling about like
a torrent, trying to go past the limit.
そして 今まさに奔流し
渦巻く感情が
ついに限界を超えようとしていた！
That was...
（ナレーション）
それは…
Rage.
怒り
To think that you were
such a powerful esper...
（エクボ）
これほどの超能力者とは…
No wonder the smile mask didn't work.
スマイルマスクが通じないわけだ
マスク？
あれにも細工があったのか
Mask? So there was a trick to that, too?
I didn't even notice
because it was so weak.
“力”が弱すぎて
気付かなかったよ
まあ いいや
Oh, well.
If the policy of your religion
is to kill the outsiders,
（モブ）
グループの仲間外れを殺すのが
あんたの宗教の方針なら
come at me with everything you've got.
本気で来い
That might be easier than
making me laugh.
笑わせるよりは 簡単かもしれない
"Come at me with everything you've got"?
（エクボ）
“本気で来い”だと？
お前を消すのに
Two seconds is plenty of time
to make you disappear, brat!
Evil Spirit:
High-Level
Dimple
２秒もありゃ
足りるぞ 小僧！
You're just livestock without emotions!
（エクボ）
感情のない家畜が 人並みに
怒ったフリすんじゃねえよ！
Don't try to act like you're actually angry!
How about you cry next?
次は 泣いてみるか？
おわっ！
Oho, how flashy.
ほほ～ ほう 派手だな
ん？ おっ？
何だ？ これ
What is this?
くう…
こいつは参ったぜ
Well, I'll be damned.
この俺がフル霊力で
戦うはめになるとはな！
I never thought I'd have to
fight with my full powers...
You may be the real thing, brat,
but this is where you die!
このガキ 本物だな
ここで くたばんな！
んがっ！
Wha...
何だと！
What?!
うおっ
うお うお うお おお！
ああっ…
Y-You're...
おっ お前…
They came out upon your request.
（モブ）
リクエストに応えて出てきたよ
These are my emotions.
これが僕の感情だ
This is what happens if I let them show.
身を委ねると こうなる
ば… 化け物か？ てめえ！
A-Are you some kind of monster?!
But...
だが 霊(レー)ザービーム！
Wraither Beam!
しゃあ～ 直撃！
Yes! A direct hit!
The number of fights I've endured
くぐってきた修羅場の数が
勝敗を分ける～！
is what decides the victor and loser here!
（モブ）
僕は…
I'm... terrible.
最低だ
Ah.
（エクボ）
あ…
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
You want to be able to get a clue?
空気が読めるようになりたい？
Social skills like that are beyond you.
そんな上等な処世術
お前には無理だろ
The only ones capable of them
have common sense and experience.
（霊幻）
空気が読めるのは
常識と経験のあるヤツだけで
On the other hand,
your existence itself no sense.
存在が非常識なお前には…
（モブ）
ああ…
Hey, why are you bummed out
about that now?
（霊幻）
おい 何を今更なことで
ヘコんでんだよ？
Because I'm such a downer, I ruined
a whole bunch of people's fun.
（モブ）
僕のノリが悪いせいで
楽しそうな人たちの空気が
台なしになった
Huh? Why do you have to be like them?
フン！ なぜ お前が
そいつらに合わせる必要がある？
You're the protagonist of your own life.
お前の人生の主役は お前だろ？
ああ…
僕のせいで そのグループは
なくなってしまったんです
That whole group is now gone because of me.
All they were doing was laughing...
みんなで笑っていただけなのに…
Well, your inability to get a clue
is pretty destructive.
（霊幻）
お前の空気の読めなさは
破壊的だからな
Get a Clue
What happened? You can tell me all about it.
（霊幻）
何だ？ 詳しく話してみろ
Huh? What were we...
（女性信者）
あれ？ 私たちは 一体…
Dimple-sama is passed out.
（男性信者）
エクボ様も寝てるぞ
Did he always look like that?
（男性信者）
こんな顔だったか？
Wasn't he trying to make some
boy smile, but he wouldn't?
（男性信者）
確か 少年を
笑わせようとして
笑わなかったんだよな
（男性信者）
あの少年は 一体
誰だ？
Who was that boy?
Let's look for him.
（男性信者）
捜そう
He might be the true messenger of God.
彼こそ
神の使いかもしれない
I see... so typical mind control.
（霊幻）
ああ なるほど
典型的な
マインドコントロールだ
That's not salvation. He was just
having them depend on him.
（霊幻）
救いじゃねえ
ただ
依存させてるだけだ
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
It's a popular con based on
crowd psychology,
集団心理を用いた詐欺に
多い手口だが
but considering you're hyper dense,
it didn't work on you.
ハイパー空気の読めない
お前には
効果がなかったと
ああ…
Which means, Mob,
（霊幻）
つまり モブ… お前は 今日
today you happened to saved some people
that only you could have saved.
お前にしか
助けられない人々を
偶然 助けた
ということになるな
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 0%
（鳥のさえずり）
Shige, wake up!
（モブの母）
茂(しげ) 起きなさい！
You're going to be late.
遅刻するわよ～！
（モブ）
う～ん… あ～あ
（エクボ）
おはよ
Good morning. Isn't it a
lovely morning, Partner?
いい朝だな 相棒！
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  0%
（モブ）
え？
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  1%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  2%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  3%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  4%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion:  5%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 15%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 16%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 17%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 18%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 19%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 20%
Mob gets dragged into an idiotic event
run by idiots for idiots.
（霊幻）
バカどもの バカどもによる
バカどものためのイベントに
巻き込まれてしまったモブ
The one that then appears before him
is a violent yet handsome guy.
その前に現れたのは
乱暴者のイケメン男子だった
What are you going to do, Mob?!
どうするつもりだ？ モブ
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 4:
次回「モブサイコ100」
第４話
“馬鹿オンリーイベント　同類”
"Idiots Only Event ~Kin~"
DVD? That's an excellent decision!
Idiots Only Event
~Kin~
ＤＶＤ？ とても正しい判断です！